



07539147935



claredotm@gmail.com



claremorgan.netlify.app



Edinburgh

# Summary -

I am an aspiring front-end developer with entry-level experience, specialising in web development, UI design, HTML, and am learning ReactJS. I enjoy finding ways to improve the UX, whilst enhancing front-end design, by using my previous experience with Visual Merchandising. I have 10 years worth of customer service experience which has given me an incredible foundation in leadership and teamwork. I am eager to learn new skills, whilst expanding on the knowledge I have gained through receiving a verified front-end development diploma from SheCodes.

## Skills

- Time Management
- Strong Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- Leadership & Managerial Skills
- Visual Merchandising & Display Design

## Languages & Libraries

- HTML
- React
- CSS
- Axios
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Python

## Education

## QUEEN MARY, UNIVERSITY OF LONDON

2012 - 2014

BSc Certificate of Higher Education in Biologcal Sciences – 2:1

## BURNTWOOD SCHOOL & SIXTH FORM, LONDON

2005-2012

A-levels – A, A, B, B in Maths, Textiles, Biology and Chemistry respectively

# Experience

## STORE MANAGER

I. J. Mellis Cheesemonger

Dec 2022 - March 2024

Managing the I. J. Mellis Cheesemonger on Victoria Street was an exciting experience, with hundreds of tourists visiting the street every day. It was a joy working for a family run business that was environmentally conscious and focused on supporting smaller suppliers to provide luxury goods. My main responsibilities included;

## **Driving Sales:**

- Analysing sales figures weekly to drive sales using creative new ideas, which helped me to improve sales consistently despite the cost of living crisis
- Building relationships with local tour guides to deliver bespoke experiences for groups of up to 20
- Gaining expansive product knowledge to provide tailored customer experiences

## Stock & Display:

- Regularly adjusting displays to reflect current trends, whilst enticing customers with our tasteful (and tasty) products
- Placing orders, receiving large deliveries and inputting stock data in to the POS system
- Regulating stock rotation to reduce wastage and conducting monthly stocktakes

### Staffing:

- Responsible for hiring new staff, including organising and conducting interviews
- Performing in-depth inductions for successful candidates including hands-on training
- Building a close-knit team, whilst also building relationships with other shops within the company
- Giving staff extensive customer service training including performing regular progress meetings to access skills and how I could support staff in improving
- Building weekly rotas reactive to events and holidays

#### ASSISTANT GENERAL MANAGER

The Bonnington Leith, Bar & Restaurant Sep 2020 - Dec 2022

I had the pleasure of being part of the re-opening of The Bonnington and although we struggled through many hardships including COVID restrictions, price increases and staff shortages, I believe I gained incomparable skills and resilience due to this. During this new venture my tasks were comprised of;

#### Stock:

- Placing orders, receiving deliveries and organising the cellars
- In charge of stock control, calculating GP for all products including food to implement competitive pricing & price increases
- Building relationships with suppliers and local brands, supporting local businesses

#### Staffing:

- Supervising staff on a day-to-day basis whilst running shifts
- Building close relationships with staff to keep morale high, whilst championing mental health to create a safe and healthy work environment
- Training staff using online resources and in person training sessions to help them reach their potential
- Building weekly rotas reactive to events and holidays

## Account Reconciliation:

 Organising invoices and paperwork to pay suppliers promptly

Social Media/Online Presence Management:

- Building all business socials to gain a strong following and online presence, taking Instagram following from 200 to over 2,600 within a year
- Creating vibrant, interesting and relevant content to bring in new customers and loyal customers alike
- Coordinating with web designers to create an engaging website that reflected the companies brand and ethos
- Working closely with graphic designers to launch new food and cocktail menus every season

References upon request, thank you for your time and consideration

### **VISUAL MERCHANDISER & SIGN-WRITER**

LUSH Cosmetics, Flagship (Oxford Street) Jan 2017 - Sep 2020

Working as a Visual Merchandiser at LUSH's flagship store was a challenging and fast-paced working environment. This allowed me to use my job role as a creative outlet and push the boundaries on how innovative and engaging my displays could be.

As part of my role, I regularly spent time;

- Analysing and comparing sales figures, identifying areas of opportunity to increase sales.
- Keeping up with trends within the competitive market to better understand the store's sales compared with other high street brands
- Ensuring I had an up-to-date understanding of stock levels and reactively merchandising any products that had sold out, this required quick thinking and concise communication with other members of my team
- Regularly training staff from multiple teams across the store, keeping teams up to date with companywide VM guidelines to maintain brand integrity
- Launching new and exciting products before any other store worldwide, as such, being expected to maintain the highest of standards and showcase products on a grand scale. This required me to organise my time accordingly and to create comprehensive planograms for my team and other teams to follow
- I also received extensive training on the LUSH branded signwriting font and am a signed off signwriter

### **BAR SUPERVISOR**

Tooting Tram and Social Bar & Nightclub, London Oct 2014 - Jan 2017

- Supervising team of 15-20 staff members in a busy 400-capacity venue
- Training new staff members individually and in organised staff meetings
- Key-holder Trusted with opening and closing the venue, whilst also undertaking cash handling procedures at the end of the night
- Conducted daily stock counts ensuring stock control was accurate and completed monthly stock takes
- Regularly managed large deliveries